KANIKA PARIKH

parikhkanika9@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/kanika-parikh-0a2554165/ | https://github.com/KanikaParikh

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Experienced in project life cycle from design to implementation to testing and modifying. Reliable computer science student with skills in leadership and commitment. Expert at leading and coordinating with others on projects throughout the history of academic excellence. Dedicated to work until projects are completed and meeting the highest standards. Valuable team player with personable and dedicated nature.

EDUCATION

HONORS BACHELOR'S IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

2018 - 2021 (Expected)

Lassonde School of Engineering, York University Overall GPA: 7.18

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Web Development Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Node.js, jQuery.
- Proficient in Python, Java, R, C, C++.
- Relational Database: SQL, PostgreSQL.
- IDE and Framework: Flask, Django, MS Office, GitHub, PyCharm, jupyter, git Bash, Atom, Eclipse, Android Studio, Visual Studio Code.
- Operating System: Windows, Linux, Unix, MacOS.
- Professional: Problem Solving, Critical Thinking, Communication, Teamwork, Creative, Responsible,
 Attention to detail and Commitment.
- Exceptional Skills in Algorithms, Data Structures and Software Design.
- Knowledge of Calculus, Discrete Math, Algebra, Statistics, Probability, and 3D Math

CERTIFICATIONS

- Intro to ML: Natural Language Processing (GDG Cloud Toronto)
- Introduction to Data Science (<u>Cognitive Class</u>)
- R Essentials (Cognitive Class)
- Python for Data Science (Cognitive Class)
- Python (<u>Udemy</u>)
- Learning GitHub (LinkedIn Learning)
- Earned 5-star Badge in Hacker Rank for Python and SQL (<u>Hacker Rank</u>)
- SQL for Data Analytics (Udemy Currently in progress)
- Machine Learning with Python (Cognitive Class Currently in progress)

PROJECTS

Book Review Website: https://github.com/KanikaParikh/Book_Review_Website

- Built a review website where users can register and log in to search books, leave review for individual books and see the reviews made by others.
- It uses third party API by Goodreads to pull in ratings from broader audience. Used PostgreSQL to manage database and Python, Flask to make this dynamic website and Html & CSS to make it more User-Friendly.

Tic Tac Toe Game: https://github.com/KanikaParikh/TicTacToe

- Artificial Intelligence based game using Minimax algorithm such that AI never fails to win.
- Worked on tictactoe.py file rest of the code was already given. (CS50 Project0: Introduction to Artificial Intelligence). Fixed bugs and checked the working of game in Graphical interface.

Chess Game: https://github.com/KanikaParikh/Chess Solitaire (School Project)

- Made mini version of chess of 4 * 4 grid and 6 chess pieces from scratch in a group of 2. Using Software
 Design Principles to develop the Single-player game.
- Tested the project in GUI and Batch mode (using Oracle) for the desired outcomes. Fixed minor bugs with the pre-installed debugging feature.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Team Member – Tim Hortons

April 2019 - Present

Contributed to team success by completing jobs quickly and accurately. Possess the ability to manage multiple tasks at one time.

Tutor – Excel Lassonde Sept 2018 – April 2019

Helped students with subject's knowledge as well as general abilities in learning, studying, and retaining information. Taught students how to study, take notes and complete test questions.

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Enactus Club (Project associate)

Sept 2019 – March 2020

Money Mind Project - a series of workshops that help students improve their financial literacy skills, become more independent. We collaborate with different bank institutions to provide a detailed description of financial essentials to educate people on a large scale.

York International (Orientation and Event Volunteer)

Sept 2019 - March 2020

Frosh Leader – Lassonde School of Engineering

Sept 2019

York Federation of students Sept 2018